<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dan Shiebler</title>
    <description>My musings on math and code</description>
    <link>http://dshieble.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://dshieble.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>R and R^2, the relationship between correlation and the coefficient of determination.</title>
        <description>
          
          There are 2 closely related quantities in statistics - correlation (often referred to as ) and the coefficient of determination (often referred to as ). Today we’ll explore the nature of the relationship between and , go over some common use cases for each statistic and address some misconceptions. Correlation...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dshieble.github.io/2017-06-25-metrics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dshieble.github.io/2017-06-25-metrics/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Understanding Neural Networks with Layerwise Relevance Propagation and Deep Taylor Series</title>
        <description>
          
          Deep neural networks are some of the most powerful learning algorithms that have ever been developed. Unfortunately, they are also some of the most complex. The hierarchical non-linear transformations that neural networks apply to data can be nearly impossible to understand. This problem is exacerbated by the non-determinism of neural...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dshieble.github.io/2017-04-16-deep-taylor-lrp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dshieble.github.io/2017-04-16-deep-taylor-lrp/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Exploring Assumptions with Monty Hall and Blue Eyed Islanders</title>
        <description>
          
          Let’s talk about making assumptions. Each time you form an opinion on something, you don’t re-examine each of the beliefs that contributed to that opinion. For example, when you order food at a restaurant, you pick the foods that you think will taste good. You don’t spend hours questioning the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dshieble.github.io/2017-02-12-monty-hall/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dshieble.github.io/2017-02-12-monty-hall/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Introduction to Algebraic Groups for CS People</title>
        <description>
          
          One of my favorite classes in college was Abstract Algebra. It was my first non-CS non-elementary math class, and I took it because I knew I didn’t want to graduate without having broadened my mathematical horizons beyond CS. As it turned out, Abstract Algebra felt pretty familiar. Many of the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dshieble.github.io/2017-01-02-group-theory/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dshieble.github.io/2017-01-02-group-theory/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Computation Theory Part 2 - Complexity Classes and NP Completeness</title>
        <description>
          
          Welcome to part 2 of the Computation Theory series! In the last post, we discussed decidability and the halting problem. In this post we will talk about complexity classes. Time Complexity If you’re not used to reasoning about algorithms and their complexity, there is an enormous amount of great material...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://dshieble.github.io/2016-11-19-np-complete/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dshieble.github.io/2016-11-19-np-complete/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Computation Theory Part 1 - The Halting Problem</title>
        <description>
          
          When you think about the most important fields of mathematics for a data scientist to know, you’ll almost certainly name calculus, probability/statistics, and linear algebra. These fields form the underpinnings of the most popular data analysis, signal processing and machine learning techniques. But in my experience, I’ve found that there...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dshieble.github.io/2016-10-15-halting-problem/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dshieble.github.io/2016-10-15-halting-problem/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Parallel Progress Bar - An easy way to run parallel jobs in python</title>
        <description>
          
          In this post I’m going to share a simple method that will turn any list comprehension into a high performance parallel job with a progress bar. tqdm If you are a python programmer who hasn’t worked with tqdm before, I’m about to change your life. With just 6 characters, tqdm...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dshieble.github.io/2016-09-14-parallel-progress-bar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dshieble.github.io/2016-09-14-parallel-progress-bar/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Musical TensorFlow, Part 2 - How to build an RNN-RBM for longer musical compositions in TensorFlow</title>
        <description>
          
          Welcome to part 2 of the Musical TensorFlow series! In the last post, we built an RBM in TensorFlow for making short pieces of music. Today, we’re going to learn how to compose longer and more complex musical pieces with a more involved model: the RNN-RBM. To warm you up,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dshieble.github.io/2016-08-17-musical-tensorflow-part-two-the-rnn-rbm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dshieble.github.io/2016-08-17-musical-tensorflow-part-two-the-rnn-rbm/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Musical TensorFlow, Part 1 - How to build an RBM in TensorFlow for making music</title>
        <description>
          
          Generative models are awesome. TensorFlow is awesome. Music is awesome. In this post, we’re going to use TensorFlow to build a generative model that can create snippets of music. I’m going to assume that you have a pretty good understanding of neural networks and backpropagation and are at least a...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dshieble.github.io/2016-08-10-musical-tensorflow-part-one-the-rbm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dshieble.github.io/2016-08-10-musical-tensorflow-part-one-the-rbm/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
