<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dan Shiebler</title>
    <description>A place for me to share some of the things that I spend my time on.</description>
    <link>http://dshieble.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="http://dshieble.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Parallel Progress Bar - An easy to use wrapper for concurrent.futures and tqdm</title>
        <description>
          
          In this post. I’m also going to share a super easy-to-use method that you can use to turn any list comprehension into a high performance parallel job with a progress bar. tqdm If you are a python programmer who hasn’t worked with tqdm before, I’m about to change your life....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dshieble.github.io/2016-09-14-parallel-progress-bar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dshieble.github.io/2016-09-14-parallel-progress-bar/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Musical TensorFlow, Part 2 - How to build an RNN-RBM for longer musical compositions in TensorFlow</title>
        <description>
          
          Welcome to part 2 of the Musical TensorFlow series! In the last post, we built an RBM in TensorFlow for making short pieces of music. Today, we’re going to learn how to compose longer and more complex musical pieces with a more involved model: the RNN-RBM. To warm you up,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dshieble.github.io/2016-08-17-musical-tensorflow-part-two-the-rnn-rbm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dshieble.github.io/2016-08-17-musical-tensorflow-part-two-the-rnn-rbm/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Musical TensorFlow, Part 1 - How to build an RBM in TensorFlow for making music</title>
        <description>
          
          Generative models are awesome. TensorFlow is awesome. Music is awesome. In this post, we’re going to use TensorFlow to build a generative model that can create snippets of music. I’m going to assume that you have a pretty good understanding of neural networks and backpropagation and are at least a...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dshieble.github.io/2016-08-10-musical-tensorflow-part-one-the-rbm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dshieble.github.io/2016-08-10-musical-tensorflow-part-one-the-rbm/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
